westminster.gov.uk 2015-03-20

# Website Privacy Policy | Westminster City Council

Westminster City Council will endeavour to safeguard the privacy of its website visitors. 

### What information do we collect?

We will collect personal details appropriate to the service you require. In some areas, this may simply mean registering your name, address and email details. Other on-line forms will require more information.

### What do we use personal information for?

There are various reasons that we need to collect personal data. For example, we may need your contact details for correspondence purposes. Similarly, we may need information because of legal requirements. Subject to your agreement, we may contact you to let you know about new online services, or get your feedback on how we're performing. In any event, we will only ever ask for information that is absolutely necessary and does not constitute an invasion of privacy.

### Allowing your details to be used across other council services

We're in the process of transforming our services in line with the[ Better City, Better Lives](https://www.westminster.gov.uk/better-city-better-lives) 5 year programme. This is part of our commitment to improve the quality of people's experience when they contact us.

We all get frustrated on occasion when we have to repeat the same basic information over and over again. Because of this, we're focussing on making it easy for people to do business with us, whenever and however they choose, all through a single contact, which should remember the relevant information.

By allowing your details to be used across other council services, you are allowing us to re-use information to minimise the time taken when you contact us in the future.

### Rights

Please note that in agreeing to share these details you have not forfeited your rights as prescribed under the Data Protection Act 1998 and the Council will continue to apply the same level of care to safeguard your privacy as we always have done. Your service entitlement from the Council will not be affected should you decide not to allow your data to be shared in this way. For more information about how we process personal data please see our Fair Processing Notice.

### Email Messages

We are keen to ensure that we are providing our citizens with services that they need. Consequently, you may receive occasional e-mail messages from Westminster City Council on matters that we consider may be of interest to you, if you have provided your email address to us for this purpose.

### Information to improve our site

We collect web statistics automatically about your visit to our site based on your IP address. This information is used to help us track what people are doing on the site so that we can improve it. We don't use this information to identify you as an individual and you will remain anonymous, unless you're asked to identify yourself by completing a form or an online transaction.

### Cookies

If you complete our online registration process, or subsequently login to the site, we will use cookies to remember your preferences during your current visit, and any future visits provided the cookie was not deleted in the interim. Cookies can be deleted at the end of each visit by logging out of the site. Your browser help text will contain information about how to refuse cookies from our site should you wish. Refusing cookies from our site will not affect your ability to perform online transactions, although we will not be able to display content that is relevant to you on certain pages, nor pre-fill forms with your name and contact details where relevant.

Other Cookies - we use Google Analytics on our site in order to know what is of most interest to our customers.  Using the data collected we can then gear our website to providing a more effective website for our customers.  Personal information is not collected in this process.  We also use a product called Logo_Net.  This code helps us track the route customers take through our website.  Again we do not collect personal information.  We want to ensure you reach your destination as quickly as possible and we will offer advice on what we think you may be looking for.  For example, you may see suggestions on the right hand side of some pages or you may see a chat feature in order for you to have an online conversation with a member of staff. We would like you to continue to use our site with cookies switched on but if you are concerned you have the ability to turn them off though it will mean certain features of the site won't be available to you.  For independent advice and information on how to disable cookies please see below.  

### Cookies - Further Information

Some independent information about cookies is available below: 

### Access to Information - Data Protection and You

Under the Data Protection Act 1998, you can make a formal request for the following information

  * clarification that your personal data is being processed by the Council
  * a description and copy of such personal data
  * the reasons why such data is being processed
  * details of to whom they are or may be disclosed

### Forms

If you wish to access information held by the Council about you, please complete and return the form to the address below. Should you wish to access CCTV footage captured by the Council, please complete and return the CCTV request form.

Remember to provide proof of identification with all applications otherwise we cannot process your request. 

You may view the Council's Data Protection Notification (registration number: Z5674504) by visiting the [Information Commissioner's web site](http://ico.org.uk/esdwebpages/search).

  * [The council's Data Protection Policy is available to view via the Publication Scheme](http://transact.westminster.gov.uk/publications/)

### Contact

If you have any concerns regarding data protection contact the [Data Protection/FOI Team](http://transact.westminster.gov.uk/forms/form_detail.cfm?id=186) online or in writing.
